SRUJAN SHARMA

Sr. Solutions Analyst

Business and data analyst with 5 years of experience across diverse industries. Expertise in analysis and testing of business requirements to drive deployment of applications, business processes and system solutions. Highly analytical and detailed with documented track record in full software development life cycle (SDLC) methodologies and Agile techniques



Work History

2019-03 -2020-06

Senior Solutions Analyst

CLARA Analytics, Santa Clara, USA, CA

- Client-facing Sr. Solutions Analyst for an early-stage startup in the insuretech space which uses Predictive Analytics to mitigate risks associated with worker's compensation claims.
- Led Analytics & Customer Relations for Multiple clients.
- In-charge of end-to-end customer onboarding process Coordinated with cross functional teams to ingest client data, run product pipelines, generate predictive models & populate application.
- Translated customer business needs to technical requirements. Used JIRA & Confluence to report issues, bugs and enhancements requests based on customer feedback.
- Created & automated reports for cost-benefit analysis, ROI projections
 & Model validation Visualized reports using Excel, Tableau & Superset
- Conducted operational reviews for clients & recommended process changes based on integration with our platform.
- Held Quarterly Business Reviews with key business stakeholders to discuss ROI, product adoption & ongoing projects.
- Achieved up to 300% ROI for multiple clients & significantly reduced overall claims costs by onboarding them to our platform and optimizing their business processes.

2018-06 -2018-12

Product Management Intern

Baker & Taylor, Charlotte, USA, NC

- Product manager for a leading book distribution company
- Led team to build a Recommendation System for online library system to drive up customer engagement.
- Conducted meetings, allocated resources, planned product roadmap and worked on integration with existing systems,
- Developed python-based data mining tool to collect data from multiple systems (AWS, Oracle, Hive) into a single database,
- Modeled user data to generate similarity matrix & assign user-book combinations a probability score using scikit-learn package in Python,
- Conducted A-B testing, model analysis and QA testing using agile methodology before doing stable version releases to product,
- Integrated recommender system with website using REST APIs –
 Achieved 10% increase in avg user reading time & proportionate increase in the weekly number of books checked out.



Contact

Address

San Jose, CA, 95112

Phone

240-353-8095

E-mail

Srujan.sharma@rhsmith.umd.edu

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/srujansharma/



Data Analysis

Business Analysis

ETL Process Setup

Data Mining & Warehousing

Statistical Analysis

Machine Learning

Technical Project
Management

Risk Management

Customer Relations

Data Analyst - Research Assistant 2018-01 -2018-05

University of Maryland College Park, College Park, MD

- Data Analyst partnering with an Indian matrimonial website,
- Led research to improve matchmaking on the platform,
- Defined KPIs to track performance of current matching system.
- Extracted, cleaned & normalized 150 Gb data from multiple sources.
- Analyzed user data to develop new matching system, leading to a rise in user match rates & 15% increase in engagement.

Data Analyst 2017-02 -2017-07

JN Bentley Skipton, Skipton, UK

- Worked as part of the ERP implementation team. Migrated the existing legacy system to a new age system (Xpedeon).
- Led cross-functional teams to analyze and understand operational impacts and opportunities of technology changes.
- Defined KPIs to track product adoption; Created testing scenarios to analyze system performance & issues.
- Designed an automated system for invoice handling leading to an initial saving of \$70,000 & long-term profits.

Data Analyst 2015-10 -

2017-02

2015-10

SGE Projects Pvt Ltd, Mumbai, India

- Lead Data Analyst for a Real-Estate Redevelopment firm.
- Developed a Random-Forest based model for profitability assessment by extracting past locale data to indicate growth.
- Successfully priced multiple tenders for potential construction sites leading to better bids & increased profits.

Team Leader 2015-06 -

CREA Summer Academy, Utrecht, Netherlands

- Led a team of international students from 6 countries in a competition based on startup ideas and execution strategies.
- Innovated an idea for a smart water meter product using Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning technologies.
- Compiled product requirement, customer analysis, marketing strategies & ROI projections to secure the 1st place in Utrecht and advance to the ICT international conference 2015.
- Expanded our product idea by integration of a mobile application; Presented with the Jury Special Mention Award by a special panel of investors at the ICT 2015 conference.

Education

2017-08 -Master of Science: Information Systems 2019-01

University of Maryland, R.H. Smith School of Business - College Park, MD Graduated at the top of the class with a GPA of 3.9

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science 2012-08 -



Python

SQL

Tableau

Salesforce

Big Data Storage (Hadoop, Teradata, AWS, Oracle, GCP)

Big Data Scripting (Spark, Hive, Glue, Airflow)

Advanced Excel

AWS (S3, Athena, sagemaker)

Apache (Spark, Airflow, Superset)

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

C/C++/Java

MS Office



Certifications

Google Adwords

Google Analytics



Interests

Basketball

Cycling

2016-05

Vidyalankar Institute of Technology, Mumbai University - Mumbai, India